

About Me: I'm Riann (pronounced Ryan).

I am an experienced, creative, and passionate student-centered educator with over 15 years of classroom experience, looking to undertake the role of an elementary teacher. My biggest strength in teaching is in utilizing my dedication to children's educational needs and development, with the goal of creating a personalized learning environment in a way that encourages creativity and higher-order thinking, resulting in increased student knowledge, confidence, and success. I am dependable and flexible, and successful in planning and implementing quality lessons and instruction.

As a passionate teacher, I believe all students can learn at high levels and that this can be achieved by building and maintaining positive, inclusive, and equitable relationships in and around the classroom. My goal is to nurture an engaging and collaborative learning environment that contributes positively to each child's success and social emotional growth.

Professional Experience

Bright Minds Learning Adventures, LLCBoulder. CO

Owner & Learning Pod Teacher Aug 2020 – Jun 2021

- Contract teacher in all academic subjects for eight children from six families: Two 2nd graders, three 3rd graders, two 4th graders, and one 5th grader, including students with IEP and 504 accommodations.
- Observe and evaluate student performance.
- Balanced instruction between group projects and targeted age/skill specific lessons.
- Create and maintain positive educational climate for student learning.
- · Create lesson plans integrating competencies, goals, and objectives, and modify throughout the school year.
- Utilize district curricula reflecting the diverse educational, cultural, and linguistic backgrounds of students served.
- Establish and communicate clear objectives for all learning activities, including preparing and distributing parent communications.

Boulder Country Day School – Third Grade Gunbarrel, CO

Teacher Candidate – Friends School Teacher Preparation Program

Aug 2018 – May 2019

- Planned and implemented a thematic unit about the Boulder County Watershed.
- Used reflective analysis of instructional strategies to create intentional and engaging lessons, creating interactive learning opportunities for each child.

Treehouse Learning, LLC

Lead Teacher & Preschool Lead Aug 2009 – July 2018

Louisville, CO

- Researched, designed, and implemented innovative and engaging lesson plans and activities that developed intellectual, physical, and social/emotional learning.
- Successfully improved student participation in the classroom through integration of creative role-playing exercises.
- Implemented project-based learning, allowing students to become better self-learners.
- Created individualized goal sheets to differentiate and scaffold children's learning and document progress.
- Trained and mentored diverse teaching teams with successful outcomes in classroom management, behavior management, and curriculum focused strategies.

Peace of Mind Early Education

Woodbury, MN

Lead Teacher & Program Coordinator Sep 2000 – Apr 2001, July 2001 – Oct 2002, Sep 2005 – Aug 2009

- Several years of teaching experience with an average of 14 students aged between 3 and 5 years old.
- Team mentor for training and guidance of classroom activities.

Hillsborough Kids Inc.

Family Services Counselor & Care Manager

Tampa, FL

Oct 2002 - Aug 2005

- Crisis intervention, counseling, and protective supervision for children (aged 0 to 18 years).
- Researched, developed, and implemented case plans for families in the child welfare system.

Developmental Learning Center

Assistant Teacher

St. Thomas, U.S. Virgin Islands

Apr 2001 - Jul 2001

Education

B.A. Psychology (2000)

University of Wisconsin–Stout

Colorado Early Childhood Teacher Qualification (2010)

Front Range Community College

Yoga Alliance Certified Yoga Teacher (2018)

Breathe for Change–Denver

SMART-1 (Stress Management and Relaxation Techniques in Education) (2018)

Colorado State University

Colorado Initial Teacher License (2019)

Friends Teacher Preparation Program

M.A. Learning, Development, and Family Sciences (2020)

University of Colorado-Denver

Concentration in Human Learning and Development

Comprehensive Orton-Gillingham Training (2020)

Institute for Multi-Sensory Education

Recent Volunteer Experience

I Have A Dream Foundation

Tutor – Alicia Sanchez International School

Lafayette, CO

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

- Tutor small groups of fourth grade students.
- Help site staff provide academic support and a wide range of life enrichment activities.

Elephant Nature Park

Elephant Care Volunteer

Chiang Mai, Thailand

Feb 2020

- Feed, clean, and care for 84 elephants rescued from logging and tourism industries.
- Sanctuary construction and maintenance.